Stephen Kin-Man Ng

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

☐ (+1) 310-941-3409 | ► kmnq73@gmail.com | ☐ kmnq | ☐ stefantopia | ► @stefantopia

Professional Summary

Web Application Developer with 15 years of experience designing and implementing solutions in the health care industry. Brings strong expertise in various application platforms, design patterns and development paradigms. Committed to following industry best practices, maintaining communication with customers, and establishing long-term maintainability of the products. Known for developing exceptional applications from beginning to end.

Skills_

Programming Java, Groovy, PHP, Javascript, TypeScript, Python, C, C++, C#, VB.NET, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bash, &TeX

Web Grails, Laravel, Angular, React, jQuery

DatabasesMySQL, Access, SQLite, MSSQL server, MongoDBServersLinux, Window Server, AWS, Docker, Puppet

Management Project Management

Work Experience_

Department of Radiological Sciences, UCLA

PROGRAMMER/ANALYST IV

System Architect and Technical Lead

- Provide technical leadership to two large scale projects

- Design system architecture Design for next generation of Faculty academic productivity metrics application (aRVU) using latest services based architecture to improve agility and performance. The application is implemented using RESTful API backend with Java/Grail environment and Spring Framework and Single Page Application Frontend with JavaScript/Typescript environment and Angular 7 framework
- Establish implementation and release plan to enable rapid development cycle, improve adaptation to requirements changes and increase development velocity with closed development tickets increased from 116 in 2019 to 329 in 2020.
- Collaborate with UCLA Health IT system operation team using Puppet to provision both development and production environment to ensure stability of the application

Technical Mentorship and Project Management

- Mentor and delegate work assignments to a Programmer/Analyst III
- Provide project management expertise and set up team project management environment using GitLab platform to promote collaboration and improve team communication

Department of Radiological Sciences, UCLA

PROGRAMMER/ANALYST III

Los Angeles, CA USA Dec 2015 - Aug 2018

Los Angeles, CA USA

Aug 2018 - Present

Academic Relative Value Unit (aRVU) Initiative

- Designed and developed aRVU Application to generate academic performance metrics of 100 faculties in Radiology Department to support academic personnel decisions like bonuses and promotions using Java/Grails environment with Spring Framework
- Integrated multiple internal and external data sources with automation to eliminate human data entry error
- Created user-friendly UI for more than 100 faculties, administrative assistants, fund managers, clinical trials study coordinators and department executives to enhance data accuracy and efficiency
- Application showcase in multiple cross-UC conferences to highlight usage of aRVU

Research Imaging Service (RIS) Application

- Designed and developed Web-based Application to handle clinical trials requests from at least 60 departments within UCLA to the Radiology Department using PHP/MySql environment with Laravel Framework
- The application is known as the golden standard for clinical trial management system in usability and functionality

APRIL 29, 2021 STEPHEN NG · RÉSUMÉ 1

School of Engineering Distance Learning Network, USC

PROGRAMMER/ANALYST III

Los Angeles, CA USA Dec 2012 - Dec 2015

• Collaborated with a team of developers to design and develop online learning environment and supporting tools using PHP with Oracle backend

• Designed and developed internal administration tools to support students, faculty and administrators in the remote learning environment

Department of Medicine, UCLA Medical Center

Los Angeles, CA USA

SR. INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST

Sep 2009 - Dec 2012

- Designed and developed patient medical records and data collection system for the Dept. of Medicine (DOM) outpatient program, as well as the hospital's internal medicine and urgent care facilities
- Managed all web-based systems for DOM Education Office to meet various departmental needs
- Designed and developed a web-based, HIPPA compliant physician note system that readily permits exchange of information between primary physicians, consultants and other care providers, as well as rapid recoding of necessary data for record-keeping
- Supported, maintained and expanded existing medical reminder system to tract therapies, needed diagnostic studies, follow-ups, appointment, etc. for monitoring of patient's care processes
- Created and developed a secure online patient-physician email based corresponding and prescription system
- Performed ongoing project development and site maintenance functions for various DOM websites

Department of Medicine, UCLA Medical Center

Los Angeles, CA USA

Jun 2003 - Sep 2009

PROGRAMMER/ANALYST II

- Designed, developed and maintained Web solution for the Department of Medicine
- Developed Enterprise Patient Record and Preventive Screening Reminder (Expert) System (Outpatient Signout) with connection to UCLAHealth MCCS Patient Records web services.
- Designed and maintained Website for Department of Medicine (Housestaff and Schedules)
- Constructed and designed the Website portal for Department of Medicine
- Constructed multi-hosts testing environment using SME server (customized Red Hat 7.3 Linux server)
- Developed and maintained various websites in the Department of Medicine including Office of Research Administration Website

Education_

UCLA Extension, Los Angeles PROJECT MANAGEMENT CERTIFICATION

Los Angeles, CA USA

2019

Los Angeles, CA USA

2004

University of California, Los Angeles M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (GPA 3.8)

Los Angeles, CA USA

2001

University of California, Los Angeles

M.S. IN PHYSICS (GPA 3.8)

Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Chinese University of Hong Kong

M.S. IN PHYSICS (GPA 3.8)

Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Chinese University of Hong Kong

B.S. IN PHYSICS (GPA 3.7)

Leadership Development

Professional Development Program UCLA

Los Angeles, CA USA

2019

STEPHEN NG · RÉSUMÉ APRIL 29, 2021